[Skip to 2:48. Opening Theme Music - Full translation available in Ep. 1]
[Skip to 2:48. Opening Theme Music - Full translation available in Ep. 1]
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Let's go.
Let's go
This world is flooded with colors.
這個世界五彩氾濫
Twisting and shaking, confusing our eyes.
整整恰恰迷惑我們的眼
Look with your heart, and see clearly.
用你的心认真去看
The truth is right in the courtyard.
发现真相就在处院
Hey you, good or bad, truth or lies
Hey you good or bad 真真假假
Can't escape this gray smoke of the soul.
逃不出这心灵的灰烟
Pack up all your courage.
带上你的所有勇敢
Maybe we can save this world.
也许就能拯救这世间
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
I'm ready to translate. Please provide the Chinese subtitles you'd like me to work on.
Mojo Spy
Late at night.
深夜
A black-clad robber
一个黑衣劫匪
Robbed Ms. Taylor's house.
抢劫了泰勒女士家
But only kidnapped
却只绑走了
Her little dog.
她家的小狗
And Taylor...
而泰勒
Due to extreme fright
由于惊吓过度
Was taken to the hospital.
被送进了医院
The next day
次日
Locky Qi and the others
齐乐天等人
Heading to Tyler's place
前往泰勒的家
to investigate.
进行调查
The beauty pageant mystery.
选美疑云
A special dog... a little too special.
特别的狗 有些特别
Where did you go?
你去哪里了
To pee.
尿尿
Drink that much juice again, and I'm not taking you on cases anymore.
再喝那么多果汁 我以后就不带你来破案了
What's that in your hand?
你手里拿的什么?
This? Jingjing just found it.
这个呀 是菁菁刚刚发现的
Looks like it's related to that cute dog.
好像和可爱的狗狗有关哦
Drink that much juice again, and I won't get to come on cases?
再喝那么多的果汁 破案就不带我来了？
Ms. Tyler, hello.
泰勒女士 您好
The First National Beautiful Dog Contest
全国首届美丽犬大赛
cordially invites you and your dog
隆重邀请您携带您的爱犬
to participate.
前来参加比赛
This might be a clue.
这也许是一个线索
I'm really worried about my mom.
我很担心我的母亲
I need to go see her in the hospital.
我要去医院看她
Yeah, I think we should hit the hospital too
嗯 我觉得我们也得去医院
to check on Ms. Tyler's condition.
看看泰勒女士现在的状况
And once she wakes up,
而且她一旦醒来
we might be able to get
我们也许就可以了解到
more clues.
更多的线索
How about we split into three teams?
不如我们就兵分三路
Officer Sima, you take one.
请司马警官
Accompany Mr. Niake to the hospital.
陪尼亚克先生一起去医院
Me, Locky, and Jingjing
我 乐天 菁菁
will head to the competition registration to check things out.
就去比赛报名处了解一下情况
Hawxing will stay at Shuiyunli
霍星就守在水云里
in case the criminal calls.
以免罪犯打电话过来
Sorry,
对不起
I need to investigate other leads my own way.
我还要以我的方式查询其他线索
Hmph, so proper.
哼 假正经
Main computer, activate geographic navigation.
主电脑 启动地理导航
Yes.
是
Lock onto Tuna Hospital Emergency Data Center.
锁定金枪鱼医院急救数据中心位置
Locking in.
锁定中
Mr. Niake,
尼亚克先生
don't worry too much.
你不要太担心
The doctor said the old lady just got a scare.
医生说老太太只是受了惊吓而已
She'll wake up soon.
很快就会醒过来的
L-L-L-Little Kitten, Little Kitten.
小,小,小,小猫咪,小猫咪。
Doctor, doctor, hurry, the patient's awake!
医生,医生,快来啊,病人醒了。
Password cracked successfully.
密码破解成功
Copying data.
拷贝数据中
Preparing data input.
开始准备数据输入
Cross-referencing emergency center communication logs.
核对急救中心通讯记录
Yes.
是
You emotionless monster.
你这个没有感情的怪物
Start cracking the police database.
开始破解警用数据库
Trace the address source of the suspicious number.
查找可疑号码的地址来源
Yes
是
Oh, hello there!
啊 你们好
Just got your call.
刚接到你们的电话
Didn't expect you to show up so soon.
没想到这么快就来了
Please follow me to my data room first.
请诸位先到我的资料室来
Go ahead.
请吧
Mr. Hao, I'm really sorry to trouble you.
郝先生 真是太麻烦你了
We need info on a contest dog.
我们想找一只参赛狗的资料
It's name is Little Kitten.
它名字叫小猫咪
Master is Ms. Taylor.
主人是泰勒女士
Ah, I remember. Just a moment.
啊 我记得 请等一下
Check this out.
请看
Hey, this—
哎 这
All letters and numbers.
怎么都是字母和数字
Top secret files?
绝密档案呢？
Too many people signed up.
报名人数太多了
This is totally beyond our expectations.
完全出乎我们的预料之外
So in the end, we all went with numbers.
所以最终我们都采用了编号的形式
Now it's so complicated that even I can't keep track anymore.
现在复杂的连我也记不清了
Anyone else can see this data?
还有谁能看到这些资料吗
Just me and three staff members.
只有我和三个工作人员
Those staff members
那些工作人员
Has there been anything unusual lately?
最近是不是有什么异常啊
Oh, hehe, they...
哦 呵呵 他们
They've been way too busy lately.
他们最近太忙了
When it was time to clock out,
下班的时候
I told them to go home.
我让他们回家
They actually insisted on working overtime,
他们居然要继续加班
and even slept in the office.
晚上还睡在办公室里
Looks like nothing unusual.
看来没什么特别的
I'll take my leave now.
先告辞了
Thanks for your help.
谢谢您的帮忙
Alright.
好
Feel free to contact me if anything comes up.
有什么问题再和我联系吧
Hello? (answering phone)
喂？(接电话)
She's left the hospital.
离开医院了
Okay.
好
We'll be right there.
我们马上到
Yeah, got it.
嗯 好的
Understood.
明白了
Let's go—we're heading back to Niake's place.
走 我们赶回尼亚克家
The old lady's been discharged and is home now.
老奶奶出院回家了
Has Ms. Taylor returned?
泰勒女士回来了吗
Ms. Taylor went to her room to rest.
泰勒女士回房间休息了
How is she?
情况怎么样
Niake's mother's health—
尼亚克母亲的身体
nothing serious.
没有什么大问题
She's just really worried about her little dog,
就是特别惦记她的小狗
insisted on coming home to wait.
非要回家来等
She didn't get a clear look at the suspect's face.
嫌疑人的脸她没看清楚
The criminal hasn't called either.
歹徒也没有打来电话
Any leads on your end?
你们有什么收获没有
Locky Qi,
齐乐天
got any clues?
你有什么线索吗
I think Mr. Hao at the puppy beauty contest registration desk
我觉得小狗选美报名处的
seems a bit suspicious.
郝先生有些问题啊
Oh? What's the issue?
哦？什么问题
What's wrong?
哪里有问题
Hard to put into words,
我也很难说清楚
but at the contest registration,
但在大赛报名处
there's a photo
有一张照片
that raised my suspicions.
让我起了疑心
Ha! Good news—
哈哈 好消息
a boy found a lost puppy
有个男孩发现丢失了小狗
and brought it back.
特地送回来了
This isn't my dog.
这不是我家的狗
Alright, alright,
好啦好啦
sit down.
坐下
Too bad the boy meant well,
唉 可惜送狗来的男孩一片好心
but if it's not your own dog,
但不是自家养的狗
it's really hard to tell them apart.
真的很难分清
Why are the files all letters and numbers?
档案怎么全是字母和数字
The number of contestants is way
报名人数太多了
beyond what we expected.
完全出乎我们的预料之外
So we have to use numbers instead.
所以我们只能采用编号
Now it's gotten so complicated even I can't keep track.
现在复杂的连我也记不清了
Hurry up, Uncle!
快呀 老舅
Let's go to the contest registration desk.
快去比赛报名处
I need to ask Mr. Hao a few questions.
我要问郝先生几个问题
Huh?
嗯？
Heh heh, you're back again.
呵呵 你们又来了
Mr. Hao.
郝先生
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
我想问您几个问题
Sure.
好
Little detective.
小侦探
How many dogs are competing in this contest?
请问这次参加大赛的狗有多少只呢
Uh... about...
嗯...大概...
About three or four thousand, I'd say.
大概有三四千只吧
And how many Pomeranians are participating?
那有多少只博美犬参加呢
That hasn't been tallied yet.
这个还没统计出来
Probably close to a few hundred.
估计也有将近几百只
With so many dogs competing,
参赛的狗多
naturally each breed will have a lot of entries.
所以每种类型的狗自然也就会多
So what numbering system are these dog files arranged by?
那么这些狗档案是按照什么编号顺序排列的呢
Most of the numbers were assigned by other staff.
编号大部分都是其他工作人员编写的
I can't recall off the top of my head.
我一时记不清楚了
I'd have to check.
要查一查
No need.
不用了
Now for the last question.
现在问最后一个问题
[Ending Theme Music - Full translation available in Ep. 1]
[Ending Theme Music - Full translation available in Ep. 1]
At that time, life...
当时人生
There's bound to be some unhappiness.
难免会有些不快乐
Goodbye, classic.
告别经典
It always makes you feel so down.
总是让人觉得失落
Let's see what tomorrow brings.
看看明天
Waving at me from your horizon
在你平线向我招手
The sun rises and sets every day.
每天就在日升日落
Cut to a time fantasy for more.
转进时间幻想更多
Looking forward to every second, every moment of life.
期待生命中每秒每一刻
Bright eyes are twinkling.
明亮的眼睛在闪烁
A smile that greets the sun.
迎着阳光的笑容
Cross the bridge, at the silent crossroads.
踏过桥桥中在沉默着的路口
Now for the final question.
现在最后一个问题
This dog looks just like the one my wife used to have.
这只狗和我妻子以前养的狗实在是太相像
Are you saying you suspect I'm the one who did the kidnapping?
难道你们怀疑如果真是我绑架的
How could I ever face my late wife then?
那我怎么对得起我死去的妻子呢